MATTHEW VAUGHAN

Software Engineer

(561) 313-3416 @ mvaughan404@gmail.com @ https://matt-vaughan.com



EXPERIENCE

Software Consultant

App Lighting LLC

苗 11/2018 - Present

North Andover, MA

My personal LLC for providing software consulting and engineering services through various online platforms

- Provide efficient, timely, and cost-effective Android, iOS, e-commerce, telecommunication, and customer engagement solutions to small businesses and individuals
- Utilize the 'right-tools' and keep up-to-date with Python, Node.is, React, Java, MySQL, AWS, and Google Cloud

Independent Contractor

Focus EduVation

= 10/2019 - 03/2020

Woburn, MA

Offers a portfolio of services to enable online learning for businesses and universities

• Provided assessment materials, derived from lectures, for online courses educating students of information technology and/or data science.

Associate Member of Technical Staff (Software Engineer II)

Salesforce (by aquisition of Demandware)

World leader in CRM with an inclusive corporate culture Acquired Demandware in 2015 for \$2.9B

• Utilize Java/Spring-MVC/Velocity template/HTML/JavaScript stack to implement security and platform features for a world-class SaaS ecommerce product (DemandWare) with thousands of enterprise tier clients (Kate Spade, ADIDAS, iRobot, Starbucks) and users in the hundreds of millions

Research Assistant

Tufts University

= 01/2015 - 05/2016

Medford, MA

Selective "right sized" university in Medford, Massachusetts

- Design declarative portion of a nano pass compiler in SML/NJ based on Andy Keep's work
- Implement a byte code executing virtual machine with parallel and concurrent generational garbage collection in the C programming
- Target C, JVM, LLVM, and x86_64 ASM as output languages for compilers

Software Engineer

International Business Machine (IBM)

Monolithic employer of 300,000 with a hundred-year history gambit spanning product portfolio, among the few engaging in basic research

• Utilize Java/Dojo/HTML/JavaScript/XML stack to implement and test user interfaces for enterprise order management system (used by Target, Best Buy, Walmart, etc)

Database Manager

Phoenix Technologies (by aquisition of Touchstone Software)

Software giant ubiquitous with BIOS

Acquired Touchstone Software in 2008 for \$18M

- Keep 'DriverAgent' database of drivers up-to-date with most recently released hardware drivers for all Windows OS
- Write PHP scripts to automate process and generate reports

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science minor Mathematics

GPA

University of Massachusetts -Lowell

3.9 / 4.0

= 2010 - 2013

Ph.D. (Incomplete)

GPA

Tufts University

3.7 / 4.0

= 2015 - 2016

STRENGTHS



Entrepreneurial spirit

Managing my own business for the last four years, utilizing self made Twilio docker containers running Tomcat with **Scala** in a functional paradigm, leveraging Google Api, Google Cloud, and AWS for rapid and reliable deployment



Microservices

Employing docker containerized microservices for web servers, databases, middleware, and **REST** API fulfillment



Full Stack

Working for eight years as an engineer and consultant (Touchstone Software, Phoenix Technologies, IBM, Demandware, Salesforce, App Lighting LLC) in Java, Scala, Node.js, and PHP stacks with Apache, Nginx, Tomcat, and Django servers all with HTML, CSS, JQuery, Velocity, Dojo, and React front ends

E-Commerce and Order Management

> Developing **DemandWare** platform and implementing **Sterling** order management user interfaces

Leadership

Subcontracting as many as four additional engineers to support larger contracts

Written and verbal communication Skills

164 verbal GRE score

Top 2% IQ Mensa qualified

"Photographic" memory

Perfect scores on delayed (<0.1%) and intermediate recall (<5%) and Eidetic memory indicated by **BVMT**

SKILLS

Languages (years)

Python(3)

Tools

Git Jenkins Bash SSH Virtual Box

VMWare Workstation Linux RDP AWS Docker

Kubernetes

Databases and servers

Oracle MongoDB Tomcat Apache Nginx

OpenSMTPd Django Express

SUMMARY

I started programming as a teenager and worked in the tech industry after high school. I decided to return to school to hone my skills and legitimize myself as a software engineer. I graduated summa cum laude with a bachelors degree in computer science (two courses shy of a second bachelors in mathematics). I was encouraged to continue my studies in graduate school by my professors, but had accepted a job offer at IBM. Where I worked for a year before attending Tufts University to pursue a Ph.D.

When I couldn't balance my budget (morgage payment) I reduced to part time enrollment at school to take a job at *Salesforce*.

Due to illness, I had to leave both graduate school and my engineering position in 2016. During my six year struggle I occasionally freelanced. Since making a full recovery two years ago I have freelanced to pay the bills and now wish to return to my chosen profession full time.